Finding Aid for Leroy Barnett Photograph Collection, 1928-1965
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Postcards
  - Gobles (Box 14)
    (family cabins include: Alie, Brown, Dwyer, Guth, Hartley, Hudson, Jack, Kiser, Mattmueller, McConnville, Mravics, Murphy, Olson, Petersen, Poulson, Quetsche(?), Sage, Sage Bros., John Sage, Webb)
  - Grand Haven (Box 14)
    (include The Oval; The Channel into Lake Michigan; Coast Guard station; North Shore County Park; Telephone building; The Castle)
  - Grand Junction (Box 14)
    (include Ed Shackley cabin)
  - Hesperia (Box 14)
    (include Main Street; Diamond Spur Ranch with women and a horse)
  - Holland (Box 14)
    (include Nellis Tulip Farm showing festival crowd; Van Bragt Tulip Farm showing festival crowd; Camp Keewano--dining room in use; also Nelis and Van Bragt cabins)
  - Idlewild (Box 14)
    (include Idlewild Public School; The Purple Palace dance club; Idlewild Club House; also Douglas, Elsner, George R. Hooper, George Jones, McKissic Jones, MacKnight, Nelson, Nicholson, Spizerinktum, and H.O. Wilson cabins)
  - Lake City (Box 14)
    (include Downtown; Sunset State Park)
  - Lake County (Box 14)
    (include Lake County Road Commission Building)
  - Lake George (Box 14)
    (include Lincoln Tourist Park)
  - Lakeview (Box 14)
    (include High school showing students; Lincoln Avenue; Main Street)
  - Lakewood Club (Box 14)
    (include Union Chapel; St. Mary of the Woods Catholic Church; also Damon, Hinckler, Pythias, and Squire cabins)
  - Lawrence (Box 14)
    (include Flour mill; Baybrooks Farm; also Braybrooks, Hagberg, and Jennings cabins)
  - Leland (Box 14)
    (include Fishing harbor; The Park on the Beach; Golf club depicts women playing golf)
  - Ludington (Box 14)
    (include Coast Guard station; Hamlin Lake Dam; Sauble Inn shows a shuffleboard game in progress; State park)
  - Manistee (Box 14)
  - Michillinda (Box 14)
  - Montague (Box 14)
    (include Maple grove on the Old Channel Trail)
  - Neahtawanta (Box 14)
    (include Buckwitz cabin)
  - Newaygo (Box 14)
  - Northport (Box 14)
    (include The airport)
  - Northport Point (Box 14)
    (include The Dock and Point Store)
  - Oak Park (Box 14)
    (include Camp Douglas photographs with boys and counselors in camping activities; also Bragdon cabin)
  - Old Mission (Box 14)
  - Paradise (Box 14)
    (include Upper Tahquamenon Falls)
  - Pentwater (Box 14)
  - Plainwell (Box 14)
    (include Downtown)
  - Pullman (Box 14)
    (include Baker, Hynes, and Kilby cabins)
  - Saugatuck (Box 14)
  - Saint Ignace (Box 14)
    (include Castle Rock)
  - Shelby (Box 14)
  - Shelbyville (Box 14)
  - South Haven (Box 14)
    (include Sleepy Hollow Gardens)
  - Spring Lake (Box 14)
    (include Spring Lake Country Club)
  - Twin Lake (Box 14)
    (include County park; Oslund's Store; Church; Community park; also Dr. William Foster, Major, Richert, and Segessman cabins)
  - Vestaburg (Box 14)
    (include Bass Lake Pavilion; R.E.A. Power Plant; C.D. Alexander Memorial Hall; Tabernacle, Rock Lake Assembly; also Douglas cabin)
  - Wayland (Box 14)
  - Whitehall (Box 14)
    (include Block House; Trailer park on White Lake; White Lake Golf Club with golfers; West Pier Head Light; Illinois Villa (showing people); Murray Inn showing people; White Lake Villa showing people; Downtown)
  - White Lake (Box 14)
  - Wolf Lake State Fish Hatchery (Box 14)
- Michigan National Guard
  The Michigan National Guard series documents in photographs various times when the National Guard was called up during the 1950s and 1960s. These include various tornadoes between 1953 and 1965, the moving of a hospital in Adrian in 1957, the Essex Wire Corporation strike in Hillsdale in 1964, which involved units from Grand Rapids, Battle Creek, Flint, Brian Center, and Dowagiac, and a civil disturbance in Detroit in 1968. These subseries are arranged chronologically by the earliest date in each subseries. Arrangement within each subseries is also chronological. The negatives for many of these photographs are included in the collection and can be found clipped to the back of their corresponding photographs.
  - Tornado duty 1953-1965
    - May 21, 1953 Port Huron
      - Maj. McDonald with Maj. Gen. Loveland and Maj. McCall (Box 14)
    - June 8, 1953 Flint (Box 14)
    - April 3-4, 1956 Grand Rapids
      - Col. Clarence Schnipke with Lieutenant Colonel John Brown (Box 14)
    - May 8-9, 1964 Anchor Bay (Box 14)
    - April 11-14, 1965 Grand Rapids and Comstock Park
      - Capt. Leroy Hunt with Sgt Weaver and Maj. Gen. Cecil Simmons (Box 14)
      - SP4 James Casey with Sgt. Roger Howard and PFC Herre Komdeur (Box 14)
  - Adrian--Moving patients to the new Bixby Hospital June 24, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Essex Wire Corp. strike, Hillsdale May 28-June 5, 1964
    - May 28, 1964
      - Fairground bivouac (Box 14)
      - Lieutenant Colonel Spwar with Inspector Gatoury (Michigan State Police) (Box 14)
      - PFC Lyle Otis with SP4 Leo Chekowski (Box 14)
      - Mess (Box 14)
      - Capt. Messner (Box 14)
      - Maj. Lankford with Maj. Baird, Brig. Gen. Neifert, and Lieutenant Colonel Smith (Box 14)
      - Inspector Gatoury with Lieutenant Colonels Smith and Spwar (Box 14)
    - June 1, 1964
      - Governor Romney and entourage arriving (Box 14)
      - Governor Romney with Attorney General Kelley and guardsmen (Box 14)
      - Mess (Box 14)
      - Fairgrounds (Box 14)
    - June 2, 1964
      - Governor Romney with Brig. Gen Neifert (Box 14)
    - June 3, 1964
      - Mess (Box 14)
      - Plant reopening (Box 14)
    - June 4, 1964
      - Capt. Thomas C. Sanok and wife with Lieutenant Rutkowski and wife (wives bringing money and clean uniforms) (Box 14)
      - Capt. McEvoy with Lieutenant Colonel Smith at the communications center (Box 14)
      - PFC John Perkins and SP5 Jack Thomas at mess (Box 14)
      - Picketing strikers (Box 14)
      - Radio command station (Box 14)
    - June 5, 1964
      - Senator Vander Laan with Pvt Bernie Vander Ploeg and SP4 Gerald Koster (Box 14)
      - Aerial views of Essex Wire Corp., the fairgrounds, and Hillsdale (Box 14)
      - Msgt Huntley with his wife, who brought him money (Box 14)
      - PFC Ross Page and SFC Eugene McClarey breaking down rations (Box 14)
  - Detroit--Civil disturbance April 5-7, 1968 (Box 14)
- Michigan Department of Conservation
  The Michigan Department of Conservation series documents a great variety of activities of the Department in the 1930s and early 1940s. It is especially rich in wildlife conservation photographs, including the regulation of fishing and hunting.
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (Box 14)
  - Farming
    - Michigan State College experimental farm at Chatham (Box 14)
    - Packing eggs (Box 14)
  - Mining (Box 14)
  - Oil wells
    - Mt. Pleasant (Box 14)
  - People, buildings
    - Governor Murphy (Box 14)
    - Kalkaska Trout Festival (Box 14)
    - Officer training school (Box 14)
    - Roscommon station (Box 14)
  - Safety, fires
    - Cooking pot eaten by porcupine (Box 14)
    - Fire damage (Box 14)
    - Fire prevention signs (Box 14)
  - Scenery
    - Lake Leelanau (Box 14)
    - Presque Isle (Box 14)
  - State parks
    - Interlochen (Box 14)
    - Bay City (Box 14)
  - Surveying activities (Box 14)
  - Water conservation (dams and patrol boats) (Box 14)
  - Wildlife conservation
    - Beaver trapping (Box 14)
    - Deer hunting (Box 14)
    - Duck hunting (Box 14)
    - Kellogg Bird Sanctuary (Box 14)
    - Fish census and planting (Box 14)
    - Fishing licence inspections (Box 14)
    - Pheasants (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Plane on ice of Lake Ritchie, Isle Royale (Box 14)
    - Street scene (unidentified) (Box 14)
- Libraries
  - Lapeer County bookmobile (Box 14)
  - Flushing Public Library (Box 14)
- Events and monuments
  - Holstein--Friesian Association Picnic 1927 (Box 14)
  - Lumbermans' Monument, Iosco County (Box 14)
  - 1,000,000th bushel, Benton Harbor peaches 1946 (Box 14)